伙计们  伙计们
Hey, guys. guys.
有几个女服务生要我来问你们一声
Some of the other waitresses wanted me to ask you something.
这个叫"Tresling"  它是将掰手腕需要的力量
It's called Tresling. It combines the physical strength of arm wrestling
与玩俄罗斯方块需要的头脑敏捷度相结合的终极运动
with the mental agility of Tetris into the ultimate spots.
是  很棒
Yeah, that's terrific.
但她们是要我来问  你们是否可以打住了
but they wanted me to ask you to cut it the hell out.
好  来吧  大伙  来了
Great. Come here, guys. Come on.
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you.
我们还是结束吧  打成平手  俄罗斯方块你赢了
We might as well stop. It's a stalemate. You're beating me in Tetris,
你的上肢力量就跟个同性恋差不多
but you've got the upper body strength of a Keebler elf.
同性恋?  我现在就干你
Keebler elf? I've got your Keebler elf right here.
好  打成平手
Okay, it's a stalemate.
里奥纳德  礼拜六我们会
So, leonard, will we be seeing you
在这里看到你和你的免费生日奶酪蛋糕吗
on saturday for your free birthday cheesecake?
他不能吃奶酪蛋糕
He can't eat cheesecake.
他乳糖过敏的
He's lactose intolerant.
好  那可以要胡萝卜蛋糕
Okay, he can have carrot cake.
那蛋糕上面装饰的奶油奶酪呢
What about the cream cheese frosting?
他可以掰下来不吃
He can scrape it off.
不提蛋糕了
Forget about the cake.
你怎么会知道礼拜六我生日?
How do you know that my birthday's saturday?
我占卜过你的星座  还记得?
I did your horoscope, remember?
我还想占卜你们每一个的
I was going to do everybody's,
直到被谢尔顿那典型且神经兮兮的理论所打断
Until sheldon went on one of his typical psychotic rants.
正式申明下
For the record,
那"神经兮兮的理论"是贝尔特拉姆·福尔
"that psychotic rant" was a concise summation
所做研究的简要概括
Of the research of bertram forer, who in 1948,
他于1948年通过精心设计的实验
Proved conclusively through meticulously designed
结论性地证明占星术只不过
Experiments that astrology is nothing
是伪科学的噱头
but pseudo-scientific hokum.
叽里呱啦叽里呱啦  典型的金牛座
Blah, blah, blah. typical taurus.
说真的  我们是不是周六见?
So, seriously. are we going to see you saturday?
-我想不是吧  -为什么?
Uh, I don't inink so. why not?
我不庆祝生日的
I don't celebrate my birthday.
开玩笑  你不会的
Shut up. yeah, you do.
这没什么大不了  我一直都是这样的
It's no big deal; it's just the way I was raised.
我父母只会在我取得成就的时候庆祝
My parents focused on celebrating achievements,
而被逐出产道
And being expelled from a birth canal
显然不算其中一项
was not considered one of them.
这太可笑了
That's so silly.
事实上  这还是一篇有理有据的文章
It's actually based on very sound theories.
他母亲发表在报纸上的
His mother published a paper on it.
这篇文章什么标题
Well, what was it called?
"我讨厌我儿子  因此他不能吃蛋糕"?
"i hate my son and that's why he can't have cake"?
显然易见  这是正确的
It was obviously effective.
里奥纳德长大后现在是一位实验物理学家
Leonard grew up to be an experimental physicist.
也许如果她还不让他过圣诞节
Perhaps if she'd also denied him christmas,
他还会更出色些
he'd be a little better at it.
谢谢
Thank you.
我很爱过生日
Well, I love birthdays.
起床后早饭是妈妈特制的法式吐司
Waking up to mom's special french toast breakfast,
戴上生日王冠
Wearing the birthday king crown,
和朋友们玩激光枪捉人
playing laser tag with all my friends...
是吗  看见不?
Yeah, see?
那才是孩子们该干的
That's what kids should have.
事实上  这是在去年
Actually, that was last year.
这么说你真的从来没开过生日派对?
So you really never had a birthday party?
没错  但没问题啊
No, but it was okay.
我小时候
I mean, when I was little,
还想父母可能会改变主意
I'd think maybe my parents would change
然后办个派对给我个惊喜
Their mind and surprise me with a party.
有一次生日  我上完大提琴课回来
Like this one birthday I came home from my cello
看见外面停着许多陌生的轿车
Lesson and I saw a lot of strange cars parked out front.
我走到门外时
When I got to the door,
听得见里面人在细声细语
I could hear people whispering
还闻到了表兄的巧克力蛋糕
and I could smell german chocolate cake,
那是我的最爱
Which is my favorite.
然后呢?
And?
结果是我祖父去世了
It turns out my grandfather had died.
天呐  那太糟糕了
Oh, my god. that's terrible.
那次倒有点生日派对的意思
Well, it was kind of like a birthday party.
所有的亲戚都来了  也有蛋糕  所以...
I got to see all my cousins, and there was cake, so...
这是我听过的最可怜的事了
That's the saddest thing I've ever heard.
是吗?
You think?
继续  告诉她你高中毕业舞会的事
Go ahead, tell her about your senior prom.
天才也性感 第一季 第16集
The Big Bang Theory S01E16
叫他们千万别忘了...不放花生
Make sure they remember-- no peanuts.
霍华德  城里每家泰国餐馆
Howard, every thai restaurant in town
都知道你不能吃花生
knows you can't eat peanuts.
他们看到我进去都直接说  "不放花生男来了!"
When they see me coming, they go, "ah, no-peanut boy!"
好  潘妮
Hello, penny.
里奥纳德刚走
Leonard just left.
我知道  我来跟你说呢
I know. I want to talk to you.
我们可以说什么?
What would we talk about?
就我所知我们没有什么共同语言
We have no overlapping areas of interest I'm aware of.
你知道  我对闲谈没兴趣
As you know, I don't care for chitchat.
你先让我进去好吗
Can you just let me in?
没问题  但我不认为这是什么有效的努力
Well, all right, but I don't see this as a promising endeavor.
好  直接说吧
Okay, here's the deal.
我们要在周六给里奥纳德
We are going to throw leonard a kick-ass
办个超级惊喜的生日派对
Surprise party for his birthday on saturday.
我不赞同
I hardly think so.
里奥纳德说得很清楚他不想要派对
Leonard made it very clear he doesn't want a party.
有人说..."派对"?
Did someone say... "party"?
他根本不知道他想要  因为他从来没有过
He just doesn't know he wants one 'cause he's never had one.
这倒是可能的  但申明一下
I suppose that's possible, but for the record,
我从来没玩过3P  但我仍知道我想玩
I've never had a threesome and yet I still know I want one.
霍华德
Howard,
区别在这儿...里奥纳德享受一次生日派对
Here's the difference-- the possibility exists that
还有可能在地狱毁灭之前发生
Leonard could have a birthday party before hell freezes over.
好吧  如果我真的玩3P了  我不会叫你的
Fine. if I do have a threesome, you can't be part of it.
我开个玩笑啦  你可以加入的
I'm just kidding. yes, you can.
你可以带个朋友来吗
Can you bring a friend.
生日派对真是个馊主意
I think a birthday party's a terrible idea.
我真嫉妒里奥纳德从小到大能免于这份痛苦
I envy leonard for growing up without that anguish.
痛苦?!
Anguish?!
年复一年
Year after year,
我都得忍受戴滑稽帽子的痛苦
I had to endure wearing comical hats while being
然后被迫走到那又挤又满是汗臭的快乐城堡里
Forced into the crowded, sweaty hell of bouncy castles.
更别提要把我眼睛遮住  转几圈走到一个奇怪的熊那里
Not to mention being blindfolded and being spun toward a
被其他小孩子嘲笑我没有方向感
Grotesque illess donkey as the other children mocked my disorientation.
亲爱的
Okay, sweetie,
我知道你有一些非专业人士无法治愈的伤疤
I understand u have scars that no nonprofeioional can heal, but,
但是无论如何  我们都要给里奥纳德开个生日派对
Nevertheless, we're going to throw leonard a birthday party.
我有没有说清楚我特别不喜欢跳舞
Have I pointed out that I'm extremely uncomforblble with dancing,
很吵的音乐  和其他大多由酒精引起的无聊举动?
Loud music and most other forms of alcohol-induced frivolity?
无论如何  我们...
Nevertheless, we're...
另外  我真觉得里奥纳德并不想...
In addition, I really don't think that leonard wtsts...
要么你帮我开派对  要么  上帝啊
You either you help me throw leonard a birtayay party or, so help me god,
我会到你的卧室里把你最值钱的
I will go into your bedroom and unbag all of your most valuable,
全新漫画书都倒出来
Mint-condition comic books.
然后在其中一本...你不会知道是哪本
And on one of them-- you won't know which--
-我会在上面用墨水画一个小小的笑脸  -你不能这么做
I'll draw a tiny happy face in ink. you can't do that.
如果你在一本全新的漫画书上做标记  那就不是全新的了
If you make a mark in a mint comic book, it's no longer mint.
谢尔顿  你懂啥叫勒索吗?
Sheldon, do you understand the concept of blackmail?
当然  我明白  噢...
Well, of course, i... oh.
我有个想法
Yeah, I have an idea.
我们来给里奥纳德开一个超级生日派对吧
Let's throw leonard a kick-ass birthday party.
这不是敲门密码
That's not the secret knock.
这才是敲门密码
This is the secret knock.
有什么区别啊?
what difference does it make?
设置敲门密码的所有意义就在于建立一种
The whole point of a secret knock is to establish a
非语言信号来验证某人的同行者身份的办法
Non-verbal signal to verify the identity of one's co-conspirators.
是不是拉杰和霍华德?
Is that raj and howard?
可能  但是还没有核对
Possibly, but unverified.
让我们进去不
Will you just let us in.
你很幸运  这并不是核反应堆
Luckily for you, this is not a nuclear reactor.
你们准备了什么生日礼物?
So what'd you get the birthday boy?
拉杰给他买了一个特别赞的
Well, raj got him an awesome,
限量版黑暗武士的雕塑
Limited edition dark knight sculpture
是出自阿列克斯·罗丝版本授权的蝙蝠侠
Based on alex ross's definitive batman.
而我送给他这份完美的  有费曼亲笔签名的
And I got him this amazing autographed copy
关于物理学演讲的拷贝
Of the feynman lectures on physics.
太棒了
Nice.
我要送他一件毛衣
I got him a sweater.
他可能会喜欢吧
Okay, well, he might like that.
我见过他感到冷的
I've seen him get chilly.
谢尔顿  我没有看到你的礼物啊
Sheldon, I didn't see your present.
因为我没有带礼物来
That's because I didn't bring one.
-为什么啊?  -别问
Why not? don't ask.
整个送礼物的机制是没有意义的
The entire institution of gift-giving makes no sense.
-太迟了  -比如说我花50美元给你买礼物
Too late. let's say I go out and I spend $50 on you.
我得费尽心思想你需要什么  这是件很艰苦的事情
It's a laborious activity because I have to imagine what you need,
而且你知道你需要什么
Whereas you know what you need.
现在  我们把事情简化  直接给你50美元
Now, I could simplify things-- just give you the $50 directly,
然后我生日的时候你给我50美元  这样继续下去
And then you could give me $50 on my birthday, and so on,
直到我们其中一个死了  留下个比你富50美元的老人
Until one of us dies, leaving the other one old and $50 richer.
我问问你  这样有意义吗
And I ask you, is it worth it?
叫你别问的
Told you not to ask.
谢尔顿  你是他朋友啊
Well, sheldon, you're his friend.
朋友之间就是互送礼物的
Friends give each other presents.
我同意你的论据  但不同意你的论点
I accept your premise; I reject your conclusion.
你试试告诉他这是一个没得选择的社交习俗
Try telling him it's a non-optional social convention.
什么?
What?
照我说的做
Just do it.
这是一个没得选择的...
It's a non-optional...
社交习俗
Social convention.
那倒是
Oh. fair enough.
他很有规则性的
He came with a manual.
提问  我怎么在派对之前
Question-- how am I going to get leonard
给里奥纳德准备一份礼物?
a present before the party?
我不会开车而且在步行范围内
I don't drive and the only things available within
能去的只有一家泰国菜餐馆和一个加油站
Walking distance are a thai restaurant and a gas station.
我看我能打包一份
I suppose I could wrap up an order of
脆炸米粉再加一些刮奖券
Mee krob and a couple of lottery scratchers.
我们这么办  我开车带谢尔顿去买礼物
Okay let's do this-- I will drive sheldon to get a present.
霍华德  你得让里奥纳德离开房间两小时
And howard, you need to get rid of leonard for about two hours.
没问题
No problem.
然后拉杰  你把东西搬到对面
And then, raj, you bring the stuff
然后开始布置
across the hall and start setting up.
如果有客人来了怎么办?
What if guests show up?
招待他们
Entertain them.
要是是女客人怎么办?
What if they're women?
一直盯着她们  让她们觉得不舒服
Stare at them and make them feel uncomfortable.
你还好吗
How's it goin'?
很好
Fine.
听着  新艺术影院正在放映
So listen, the nuart is showing the revised,
最终修订版的银翼杀手
Definitive cut of blade runner.
看过了
Seen it.
不  你看的是25周年的最终版本
No, you've seen the 25th anniversary final cut.
而这个版本有八秒钟以前没看过的片断
This one has eight seconds of previously unseen footage.
他们说这会完全改变电影的基调
They say it completely changes the tone of the film.
算了
Uh... pass.
来吧
Come on.
之后还有与哈里斯·福特替身的问答
Afterwards, there's a q & a with harrison ford's body double.
听着  我正在打光晕生命之战呢
Look, I'm in the halo battle of my life here.
这是个在哥本哈根的小孩  他没有免疫系统
There's this kid in copenhagen-- he has no immune system,
所以他24小时加7天不停地坐着打光晕
So all he does is sit in his bubble and play halo 24-seven.
你不能找别的时间跟他玩?
Can't you play him some other time?
如果你相信他的医生那就不能
Not if you believe his doctors.
天啊  闻到煤气味吗
Oh, my god, do you smell gas?
没有
No.
确实没有
Yeah, no.
那边有DVD播放机
You know, they have dvds over there.
是  但这里有DVD刻录机
Yes, but they have dvd burners over here.
里奥纳德需要一个DVD刻录机
leonard needs a dvd burner.
谢尔顿  礼物不应该是一个人所需要的
Sheldon, a gift shouldn't be something someone needs,
而应该是一件有趣的东西
It should be something fun.
一件他们不会买给自己的东西
You know, something they wouldn't buy for themself.
你意思说比如一件毛衣?
You mean like a sweater?
那件毛衣很有趣的
It's a fun sweater.
上面有一个醒目的几何图案
It's got a bold geometric print.
-是几何学使它变得有趣?  -好吧...
Is it the geometry that makes it fun? okay...
重点是我们关心某个人的表达方式之一
The point is one of the ways we show we care about people is
可以是通过把想法和想象力赋予到送他的礼物中
By putting thought and imagination into the gifts we give them.
我明白了
Okay, I see.
-所以不能是DVD刻录机了  -没错
So, not a dvd burner exactly.
一件他不会买给自己的东西
Something he wouldn't buy for himself.
一件有趣的东西  一件像...
Something fun. something like...
802-11n无线路由器
An 802-11n wireless router!
来吧  哥本哈根男孩
Here you go, copenhagen boy.
尝尝汉斯·克里斯蒂安手雷的滋味吧
How about a taste of hans christian hand grenade?
那肯定感觉不好
Oh, that could not feel good.
来啊  来...
Come on, come...
你个聪明的...
Oh, you clever...
来啊  来啊
Come on. come on.
尝尝这个!
Take that!
怎么了?
What's the matter?
这个格兰诺拉燕麦卷里面有花生!
This granola bar, it has peanuts in it!
上帝啊  你为什么吃它呢
Oh, my god. why did you eat it?
我不知道  它就放在那里
I don't know. It was just there.
如果我有把枪放在那里  你会对自己开枪吗
if I had a gun there, would you have shot yourself?
别对我吼
Don't yell at me!
我必须得去急诊室!
I've got to go to the emergency room!
-现在?  -不  等到我的舌头肿得像胸部一样!
Now?! no, after my tongue has swollen to the size of a brisket!
好  让我拿下钥匙
All right, uh, just let me get my keys.
上帝啊  上帝啊  上帝啊
Oh, god, oh, god, oh, god!
洗衣房已经没人了
The laundry is out of the hamper.
好  谢尔顿  那应该是什么?
Okay, sheldon, what was it supposed to be?
好  没有人洗衣服了!
Fine. it's out of the washer!
等甩干的时候我再打电话给你
I'll call you when it's in the dryer.
好  我们走
All right, let's go.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
那个
Um, that one.
因为有两个额外的以太网接口?
Because of the two additional ethernet ports?
-是的  -他不需要
Sure.He doesn't need them.
他已经有一台六个以太网接口的交换机了
He's already got a six-port ethernet switch.
好吧  那这个
Oh, okay, then this one.
-为什么  -我不知道
Why? I don't know.
盒子上的男人看起来很开心
The man on the box looks so happy.
潘妮  如果我要给里奥纳德买礼物
penny, if I'm going to buy leonard a gift,
我一定要买得合适
I'm going to do it right.
我不会让他经历我童年时的创伤
I refuse to let him experience the same childhood trauma I did.
我知道我可能会后悔了  不过  什么创伤?
I know I'm gonna regret this, but what trauma?
我12岁生日的时候
On my 12th birthday,
我非常想要一个钛离心分离机
I really wanted a titanium centrifuge
这样  我就可以分离放射性同位素了
so, you know, I could separate radioactive isotopes.
当然
Of course.
然而我父母却给我买了一个...
Instead of a titanium centrifuge, my parents bought me...
真是难以启齿
Wow, this is hard.
他们给我买了一辆摩托车
They got me a motorized dirt bike.
不会吧
No!
一个怎么样的12岁男孩会要辆摩托车?
What 12-year-old boy wants a motorized dirt bike?
所有的
All of them?
真的?
Really?
-是的  -哈
Yeah. huh.
好吧  我们就买这个?
Okay, so we're getting this one?
是吧
Yeah, I suppose.
好  我们走吧
All right, let's go.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你了解这个东西吗?
Do you know anything about this stuff?
我了解它的一切
I know everything about this stuff.
太好了
Okay,
我个人在开展鲜花批发业务
I have my own whwholesale flower business
我想把我的前台计算机
and I want to hook up my computer in the front entrance
和冷藏库的计算机连在一起
with the one in my refrigerated warehouse.
这个  看  我们就买的这个
Here, buy this one. Look, it's the one we're getting.
看  他很开心
See? happy guy.
不  不  不  她不需要那个
No, no, no, she doesn't want that.
她需要一个扩大范围的点对点网络
She needs a point-to-point peer network with a range extender.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我应该选哪一个硬盘  火线还是USB?
Which hard drive do I want-- firewire or usb?
这取决于你有什么总线(bus还有大巴士的意思)
It depends on what bus you have available.
我开的是雪佛兰跑车
I drive a chevy cavalier.
真主啊
Oh, dear lord.
-谢尔顿  我们该走了  -现在不行  潘妮
Sheldon, we have to go. not now, penny.
这位可怜人需要我的帮助
This poor man needs me.
你等一下  我马上招呼你
You, hold on. I'll be right with you.
你计算机是什么样的?
What computer do you have?
请不要说是一台白色的
And please don't say "a white one."
打扰一下
Excuse me.
把这个填好  找个座位坐下
Fill this out. have a seat.
不  听着
No, listen.
我们打算给我的朋友开一个惊喜派对
We're throwing my friend a surprise party and I'm
而我要让我朋友离开公寓两小时
Supposed to keep him out of his apartment for two hours.
把这个填好  找个座位坐下
Uh-huh. fill this out and have a seat.
不
No, see,
我能让他离开的唯一办法就是告诉他
The only way I could get him to leave was to tell
我吃了一个花生  因为我对花生过敏
Him I ate a peanut because I'm allergic to peanuts.
这样的话  把这个填好找个座位坐下
Oh. well, in that case, fill this out and have a seat.
听着
Look,
我只要你把我带到后面去  给我一张创可贴
All I need from you is to take me in the back, give me a band-aid  and
这样我就可以假装打了一针肾上腺素
So I can pretend I had a shot of epinephrine
然后你告诉我朋友你需要让我
And then you tell my friend you need to keep me
留在这观察一小时  一个半小时
under observation for about an hour, hour and a half.
没有别的了吗?
Is that all you need?
-没了  -给我滚出急诊室
Yes. get out of my er.
不  你不明白
No, you don't understand.
我明白  但是不好意思
Oh, I understand, but unfortunately,
我们医院不接待傻子
This hospalal is not equipped to treat stupid.
好吧  我知道了
Okay, I get it.
我知道这个世界的规则
I know how the world works.
不如介绍你认识一下赋予你们自由的领袖吧?
How about if I were to introduce to you to the man who freed your people?
除非我们的领袖是本杰明·富兰克林
Unless my people were freed by benjamin franklin
还有他五个孪生兄弟  否则你是在浪费时间
And his five twin brothers, you are wasting your time.
对不起  停车位太难找了
Hey, sorry, I couldn't find a parking spot.
-你怎么样了  -非常糟糕
-How are you doing? -bad, very bad.
真的?  你看上去像完全没有吃过什么一样
Really? you don't look like you're swelling up at all.
不如我们就去药店拿点伤风抗素剂然后回家吧
Maybe we should just pick up some benadryl at the drugstore and go home.
-我们不能回家  -为什么
We can't go home. why not?
因为...因为...
Becaus.... because...
我的胸痛!  胸痛!
Brisket! brisket!
-水  我要水  -我马上拿来
Water! need water! I'll be right back.
潘妮  我遇到状况了
penny, listen, I've got a problem.
<8-22,Penny (with Sheldon in background at the head of a large queue of customers)>我这里也是
<8-22,Penny (with Sheldon in background at the head of a large queue of customers)>Yeah, well, so do i.
<8-22,Penny (with Sheldon in background at the head of a large queue of customers)>听着  你得再拖住里奥纳德一会
<8-22,Penny (with Sheldon in background at the head of a large queue of customers)>Look, you gotta stall leonard a little longer.
我认为我办不到了
I don't think I can.
你必须办到  我们一定要同时回去喊"惊喜"
You have to. we all have to be there at the same time to yell surprise.
好吧  你必须明白
Okay, you have to understand something.
我们现在还在医院
We're in a hospital right now.
为什么  里奥纳德还好吧
Why? is leonard okay?
他很好  我也很好
Leonard's fine. I'm fine.
顺便感谢你的关心
Thanks for asking, by the way.
好了  我不需要你表达什么态度
Okay, I don't need your attitude.
听着  就再拖一会
Listen, just hold him there a little longer.
不行  我应经尽力了
Look, I've done my best,
但是他想回家  我不知道该怎么做
But he wants to go home and I don't know how to stop him.
好吧  那这样
Ok, , how about this?
你如果能再拖一会  等你到了派对上
You keep him there a little longer, and when you get to the party,
我会给你介绍我最容易上手的朋友
I'll point out which of my friends are easy?
不要耍我  女人
Don't toy with me, woman.
我有个以前非常胖没有自信而现在辣得不行的朋友
I got a hot former fat girl with no self-esteem,
还有个到处和男人上床气坏老爸的朋友
I got a girl who punishes her father by sleeping around and
以及一个喝两杯鸡尾酒
Alcoholi who's two tequila shots
就任人摆布的朋友
Away from letting you wear her like a hat.
我会搞定一切的
Thy will be done.
一切都是为了你  小弟弟
I'm doing this for you, little buddy.
我们库存也没有了
Okay, we don't have that in stock...
不过我可以为你特别定一个
But I can special-order it for you.
就是他
Him.
抱歉  先生  你不是工作人员
Excuse me, sir. you don't work here.
是  当然  但这里没工作人员
Yes, well, apparently, neither does anyone else.
-谢尔顿  我们得走了  -为什么
Sheldon, we have to go why?
一方面  里奥纳德的派对要开始了
Well, for one thing, we're late for leonard's birthday party,
另一方面  我已经让他去叫保安了
And for another, I told him to call security.
祝你好运
Good luck.
顺便提一下  一个6岁男孩都可以侵入你们的电脑
By the way, a six-year-old could hack your cocomputer system.
快走吧
Keep walking.
"1234"不是一个安全的密码
"1234" is not a secure password.
不好意思  我朋友他花生过敏了
Excusee-e-- my friend is having an allergic reaction to peanuts.
没  他没有
No, he's not.
是的  他是的
Yes, he is.
先生  是这样  我们很忙  而且...
Look, sir, we are very busy here, and i...
我的天啊
Holy crap!
快来人!
Please help me!
4号  我需要个轮床
Cocode four! I need a gurney!
马上  马上
Right away! right away!
谢谢
thank you.
对于这个国家的健康保健系统  你可以随便说啥
Say what you will about the healthcare system in this country,
假使他们害怕诉讼  他们得保证检测过所有东西
But when they're afraid of lawsuits, they sure test everything.
我真不觉得肠窥镜有任何必要
I really don't think the colonoopopy was necessary.
你知道嘛  在你症状出现之前
You know, before you got all swollen up,
我还以为你是要让我离开家
I actually thought you were trying to keep me out of
这样你们可以为我准备惊喜派对
The apartment so you could throw me a surprise party.
想起来了  今天是你的生日
Oh, right, it's your birthday.
我都忘了是你生日
I had no idea it was your birthday.
完全忘了
I completely forgot.
这个生日过得还真糟糕
Wow, what a lousy way to spend a birthday.
不过  反正都过去了
Well, it's all over now.
是有个派对  是吗
There is a party, isn't there?
可能
Maybe.
霍华德
Howard?
你生气了?
Are you mad?
我怎么可能生气
How could I be mad??
你都冒了生命危险就因为你关心在乎我
You actually risked your life because you care about me.
-当然  就是因为这个  -好吧
Yeah, that's why I did it all right.
进去吧
Here we go.
我的第一个生日派对
My first birthday party.
伙计  大伙一个小时前就都走了
Dude, everybody left an hour ago.
惊喜!
Surprise!
里奥纳德  我现在就在你的生日派对上
Okay, leonard, here I am on your birthday party.
我不知道你在哪  但这真的很棒!
I don't know where you are, dude, but it's really kick-ass!
每个人都烂醉如泥
Everyone is very, very drunk and...
看  有个女孩把上衣脱了!
Oh, and look, there's a girl taking her shirt off!
那是我的朋友卡萝尔
That's my friend carol.
提醒我  我要把她介绍给霍华德
Remind me-- I gotta introduce her to howard.
可爱的卡丽什娜  把卢布制造机晃起来!
Oh, sweet krishna, shake that rupee maker!
真遗憾  你错过了你的派对
I'm so sorry you didn't get your party.
没事
Oh, it's okay.
生日快乐
Well, happy birthday, anyways.
潘妮  你生日是什么时候?
Hey, Penny, wh...when is your birthday?